<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The humble petitions of the bailifes, port-men, and other the inhabitants of Ipswich, in the county of Suffolke.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 7KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A86783</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99872829</idno>
  <idno type="VID">156453</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240945845</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing H3483</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E135_35</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R529</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99872829</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99872829e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A86783)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 156453)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 24:E135[35])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The humble petitions of the bailifes, port-men, and other the inhabitants of Ipswich, in the county of Suffolke.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>8 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for H. Blunden,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1641. [i.e. 1642]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="geographic_name">Ipswich (England) --  History --  Sources --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1642-1649 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>John Pas </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:156453:1"/>
            <p>THE HVMBLE PETITIONS OF THE BAILIFES, PORT-MEN, AND OTHER the Inhabitants of <hi>Ipswich,</hi> in the County of <hi>Suffolke.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed for <hi>H. Blunden.</hi> 1641.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="petition">
            <pb facs="tcp:156453:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:156453:2"/>
            <head>TO THE HONORABLE the Knights, Citizens, and Burgesses, of the House of COMMONS assembled in PARLIAMENT.</head>
            <head type="sub">The humble Petition of the Baylifes, Portmen, and other the Inhabitants of the Town of <hi>Ipswich</hi> in the County of <hi>Suffolke.</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>Sheweth,</opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>Hat your Petitioners having here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tofore complained to this Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>norable Assemblie of many pres<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sures upon their consciences, and oppression in their estates and li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties, by Bishop <hi>Wren</hi> and his Officers, and the scandalous Ministers by him brought in amongst us, in the room of those godly and able Pastors, which were by him suspended, and drawn from us, or vexed even to death: And ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving had a libertie (through the favour and pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tience of this Honorable House, which we most thankfully acknowledge) to make our proofs of our suggestions, and having along time wait<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed for justice to be done upon those offenders,
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:156453:3"/>are now constrained to let this Honorable As<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>semblie know, that we still suffer under the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligne influence of some of the parties, who either are not cast out from us, or boast of their hopes to return and do as formerly; and that we are not clear of all fears of a reflux of miseries, in re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gard whereof we cannot prevail with godly and able Ministers to settle with us, whereby divers of our Parishes are without preaching, to the increase of prophannesse on the Lords day and other times amongst us.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And therefore humbly pray for the prosecution of these Delinquents to sentence and execution thereof. And further sheweth,</hi>
            </p>
            <p>That we have long languished under the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifold distempers and calamities, which have overspread and overwhelmed this whole King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, to the dishonour and hazard of the destru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction thereof, manifested in your late <hi>Remon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>strance,</hi> and are very apprehensive of the fervent zeal, and pious intentions, and unparalel'd pains, for the relief and removall thereof, That being a populous and Port Town, subsisting chiefly by Clothing and Shipping, whereof we have many able for traffique and service of the State upon all occasions, we do quickly feele and
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:156453:3"/>suffer deeply in the distrubance and decay of Trading and Merchant affairs in <hi>London</hi> and elsewhere And that we are equally sensible with the Citie, and other parts of the Kingdom, who have alreadie complained of the multiplying and encrease of the generall and publique di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stempers, threatning confusion and ruin by rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son of the delayes in relief of distressed <hi>Ireland,</hi> and the dangers threatned from thence to us; The supply of Armes and Ammunition the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bels there have had from forraign parts, and the encouragement from the Popish partie here; the number, libertie, power, and boldnesse of the Papists and their partie; The corrupt Clergie and Laitie in <hi>England,</hi> acted by the same principles with the Papists in <hi>Ireland,</hi> and encouraged by their successe, and the not executing the Laws against the condemned Priests and others, and the licence Traitors and other ill-affected per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sons have to passe the Sea, and escape the justice of <hi>Parliament,</hi> and do us mischief in other pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces; The rumours of great preparations in for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raigne parts; The not putting of the Kingdom into a posture of defence, nor the Forts and Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gazines into safe hands, The defects of Armes in our Trained Bands, now altogether unexer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cised;
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:156453:4"/>The sad and unhappie misunderstanding between the King and <hi>Parliament</hi> by evil Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellors; The interruptions of your proceedings which under God are the great securitie of our hopes; The high and destructive breaches of <hi>Parliament</hi> by violent attempts, which struck us with no little amazement and terror, The stop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ping of many good Bils and other preparations for Reformation in Church and Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wealth by the Prelates and Popish Lords in the House of Peers, The standing of Bishops and their officers in their places, The imposition and urging of the Service Book and Ceremonies, therein being the miserie of a dumbe and igno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant Ministery, the occasion and blindnesse and superstition in the people.</p>
            <p>The Petitioners therefore do in all humilitie assume that boldnesse to declare to this Honor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able Assemblie, that they have in due and high esteem your cares and travails, for the safetie and welfare of the publique; And they are unfained<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly willing, and shall be readie with their utmost power, lives, and estates according to their Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>testation, to do service both by Sea and Land, for the maintenance and defence of the true re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed Protestant Religion, his Majesties royall
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:156453:4"/>Person, the power and Priviledges of <hi>Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment,</hi> and the Members thereof, &amp;c.</p>
            <p>And do humbly pray that your serious Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cels, and unweatied Labours for the Common good, may with all alacritie and vigour be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinued, that the government and discipline of our Church be perfectly reformed, according to the light of Gods Word, A course taken for the purging of the Church, of unable and unfaith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full Ministers, and for a supply and maintenance of better, And a Reformation made in the Vni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>versities, the Nourseries of our publique Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stery, by advice of a free and generall Synod, That <hi>Ireland</hi> may be timely succoured, The Votes of Popish Lords in the House of Peers taken away; The Papists disabled from doing mischief, and the Laws put in execution against them; Delinquents brought to condigne punish<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment; That the Kingdom may be put into a po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sture of defence; Our Port Town secured; The Forts, M<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>gazines, and other strength of the Kingdom, with the guarding of the Narrow Seas, be put into the hands of such as the <hi>Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment</hi> may confide in; That the Priviledges of <hi>Parliaments</hi> may be maintained, and the breaches
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:156453:5"/>thereof vindicated; That this Honorable House be a mean to his Majestie, and the House of Peers, for their concurrence to the healing up of the breaches, and quieting the distractions, and redressing grievances, and causes of our fears before complained of.</p>
            <closer>And your Petitioners shall ever pray, &amp;c.</closer>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>